Thompson, Sanford E. Papers 5615
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Sanford E. Thompson Papers
1888-1978
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Thompson, Sanford E.
5615
8.5 cubic feet
8.5 linear ft.
Articles, first drafts, patents, photographs, papers (documents).
Personal, professional and business correspondence, notebooks, pamphlets, newletters, manuscripts, and experimental data and results.
2297065
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 30, 1987
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 21, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Sanford E. Thompson, construction engineer, scientific management practitioner, and consultant, is best known for his application of Frederick W. Taylor's principles of scientific management to various construction and manufacturing problems, in an effort to develop accurate methods of management planning. Born on February 13, 1867 in Ogdensburg, NY, he graduated from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology where he studied civil engineering and chemistry. He held several positions as engineer and superintendent of construction at a variety of plants until 1896, when he started consulting work. Between 1917 and his death in 1949 he was a partner in the Thompson and Lichtner Company, a management and engineering consulting firm. Thompson also served in a number of governmental posts between 1921 and 1943.
Scope and Contents
The papers include routine job measurement forms; charts; notes and reports; correspondence with management theorists, including Frederick W. Taylor and Frank Gilbreth; and publications and reports by Thompson. Papers of Frederick W. Taylor, contained in the Thompson papers, pertain generally to Taylor's and Thompson's collaborative efforts in the building trades (1892-1915).
The professional papers include routine job measurement forms; charts; notes and reports; correspondence with management theorists, including Frederick W. Taylor and Frank Gilbreth; and publications and reports by Thompson. Papers of Frederick W. Taylor, contained in the Thompson papers, pertain generally to Taylor's and Thompson's collaborative efforts in the building trades (1892-1915). Thompson's papers include charts, notes, reports, time cards, job instructions, and computation sheets pertaining to consulting work in job design, operations management, and work measurement studies for the following companies: Moosehead Paper Co. (1889-1890); Manufacturing Investment Co. Paper Mills at Appleton, Wisc. and Madison, Me. (1892); Mt. Tom Sulphite Pulp Co., Mt. Tom Mass. (1893); Umbagog Papers Mills (collaborative study with Frederick Taylor on work measurement, 1892); Tabor Foundry (operating under Taylor production system, 1914-1915); Forstmann Woolen Company (1939-1940); Schwarzenback Huber Weaving Company (1928-1938); and Ludlow Textile Manufacturing Company (1915).
Also, notes and drafts for books on marketing and scientific management (1940); reports on spinning mills (1936), defense production (1941), and unemployment and emergency measures for the construction trades (1921); correspondence pertaining to Thompson's work with the U.S. secretary of war on operations management and planning (1917); letters to E.C. Harwood and John Maynard Keynes on economics, unemployment and the Depression (1934-1935); professional certificates; MIT notebook (1888-1889); notebook on experiments (1896); a contract between Thompson and Taylor for collaboration on work measurement and construction studies (1895); press releases; and notes, brochures, and clippings on economics, engineering, marketing, and military spending.
The correspondence series includes Thompson's correspondence with various manufacturers and suppliers of machinery and work measurement devices; with the Boston Society of Civil Engineers on programs (1894-1948); with the Midvale Steel Company, Philadelphia, on Taylor's production system (1895); with Frank Gilbreth on concrete studies, construction, publications, and various work measurement studies (1897-1905); with Carl Barth (Bethlehem Steel Company) on Taylor's operation research (1902); with Frederick W. Taylor on concrete and work measurement studies (1915); with Mrs. Frederick W. Taylor on a biography of Taylor (1923); with William Danforth (Ralston Purina Company) on marketing, productivity and wages (1933); with E.C. Harwood (director, American Institute for Economic Research) on national economic policies (1934-1935); open letters to President Franklin D. Roosevelt on the economy (1934); and correspondence with Ordway Tead (Harper and Brothers) on the biography of Taylor (1936-1938). Also, letters on personal matters, consulting work, speaking engagements, publications (1892-1949), and three letter press books of outgoing letters to various manufacturers and suppliers, and some letters to Gilbreth and Taylor on construction, concrete, and work measurement studies (1903-1905).
The publications series includes notes, rough drafts, and correspondence regarding the production and publication of Reinforced Concrete Bridges (John Wiley, 1939), written in collaboration with Edward Smulski. Also, articles and supporting documents pertaining to various issues in economics, marketing, management, and work measurement. The subjects include scientific management, productivity, wages, unemployment, profit, cost accounting, production, purchasing, management and marketing in the apparel, construction, textile, and rubber industries, engineered marketing, technological change, defense production (1941), and post-war cost reduction (1944). Also included is a speech on the Salvation Army (1939), a speech, with program, from a "Symposium on Frederick W. Taylor" (Boston, 1933); and charts, notes, and drafts on chapters for an unpublished book on marketing (ca. 1946).
The Thompson & Lichtner Company files include statements and reports on company policy; promotional letters and brochures; and notes and reports on the following topics: job design, work measurement, bricklaying (1902), marketing, management, finance, Hoover's approach to economic problems (1930), an opinion survey of retailers and manufacturers (1946), productivity, post-war costs (1946) and various personnel management issues. Also, publications of the Thompson & Lichtner Company, and scattered letters concerning routine business matters, including letters regarding Thompson's appointment to various associations and organizations.
Correspondence between Thompson and Frederick W. Taylor concerns personal matters and Thompson's career plans (1892-1893), as well as the conduct of experiments, technology, work measurement and publications on coal, plastering, bricklaying, pig iron, and concrete and soils studies conducted by Taylor and Thompson (1892-1914). Also, correspondence of Carl Barth concerning the Bethlehem Iron Works experiments (1901-1903); and Frank Gilbreth concerning the reinforced concrete experiments (1904-1906).
Materials pertaining to Thompson and Taylor's concrete studies include notes, letters and reports on experimental procedures, specifications for pouring and mixing and strength testing (1909).
Soil and grass experiments were conducted by Thompson and Harold Van Du Zee for Taylor (1909-1915). Documents include graphs, charts, diagrams, computation sheets, and notes and instructions from Taylor on conduct of the experiments. Also, correspondence between Thompson and Van Du Zee on the conduct of the experiments, and the work measurement studies directed by Taylor (1909-1915).
Additional documents pertaining to Taylor include notes, reports and data on pig iron experiments (1901), work measurement studies, and a job design study conducted by Taylor for the Philadelphia Civil Service Commission (1912-1914); articles by Taylor on scientific management and profit sharing (1909-1912); photographs and diagrams of machinery and testing instruments; Taylor patents (1897-1902); Industrial Management (photocopy of book by Taylor and Morris Cole) (1909);correspondence of Taylor with Frank Gilbreth on concrete experiments (1908); National Consumers League on productivity and work measurement (1910-1912); and a letter to Richard A. Feiss on Taylor's visit to the Joseph & Feiss Company (1915); correspondence of Gilbreth and H.K. Hathaway on their meetings with Thompson and Taylor; notes and letters of the Stevens Institute of Technology regarding Taylor's professional papers (1963); and a document (upon Taylor's death) establishing Carl Barth, Morris Cooke, James M. Dodge and H.K. Hathaway as collaborators in Taylor's work in scientific management (1915).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6217: John D. and Valerie C. Stelling Collection of Sanford Thompson Files
Arrangement
Series I. PROFESSIONAL PAPERS, 1888-1949
Series II. CORRESPONDENCE, 1892-1949
Series III. PUBLICATIONS, 1925-1946
Series IV. THOMPSON & LICHTNER COMPANY FILES, 1906-1947
Series V. FREDERICK W. TAYLOR FILES 1892-1915
Sub-Series 1. R.W. Taylor/Sanford Thompson Correspondence, 1892-1915 Sub-Series 2. Taylor/Thompson Experiment Documents 1905-1915 Sub-Series 3. A. Miscellaneous Taylor Files 1892-1963 Sub-Series 3. B. Publications
Business cycles -- United States; Concrete construction.; Concrete testing.; Construction industry -- United States -- Management; Construction materials -- Research; Depressions--1929--United States.; Foundries -- United States; Hosiery industry -- United States -- Management; Industrial engineering -- United States; Industrial management.; Industrial management -- United States; Industrial mobilization -- United States; Industrial productivity -- United States; Management science.; Marketing -- United States; Methods engineering.; Paper industry -- United States -- Management; Profit-sharing -- United States; Rubber industry and trade -- United States -- Management; Scientific management.; Textile industry -- United States -- Management; Unemployment -- United States; Wages -- United States; Work design.; Work measurement.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Economic aspects -- United States; Business consultants.; Barth, Carl.; Danforth, William.; Feiss, Richard A. (Richard Albert), 1878-1954; Gilbreth, Frank Bunker, 1868-1924.; Harwood, E. C. (Edward Crosby), 1900-1980; Hathaway, H. K. (Horace King), 1878-1944; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Keynes, John Maynard, 1883-1946.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Taylor, Frederick Winslow, 1856-1915.; Tead, Ordway, 1891-1973; Thompson, Sanford E. (Sanford Eleazer),1867-1949; Van Du Zee, Harold.; Bethlehem Iron Works; Boston Society of Civil Engineers; Forstmann Woolen Company; Ludlow Textile Manufacturing Company; Midvale Steel Company; National Consumers' League; Ralston Purina Company; Salvation Army; Schwarzenback Huber Weaving Company; Thompson & Lichtner Company, inc.; Umbagog Paper Mills; United States. War Department
2297065
- Series I. PROFESSIONAL PAPERS, 1888-1949
  - Certificate of Am. Society of Mechanical Engineers, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Consultant to Secretary of War (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Contract between Taylor and Thompson, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Engineer's Certificate, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Job and Man Rating Course (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
  - Management Book (Chapter 4) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Management Book (Chapter 5) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Management Book (Chapter 6) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Management Book (Chapter 7) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Management Book (Chapter 18) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Manufacturing Investment Company (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Material on Apprenticeships (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1892-1893 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Scope and Contents
    includes photographs
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 17)
    newspaper articles
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Papers of E.C. Harwood (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Includes correspondence with John Maynard Keynes
  - Miscellaneous Professional Articles (Box 1, Folder 20-23)
  - Notebook, 1888-1889 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    MIT
  - Notebook, 1889-1890 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Moosehead Paper Co.
  - Notebook, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Manufacturing Investment Co. - Paper Mills at Appleton, Wisconsin and Madison, Maine
  - Notebook, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
    Mt. Tom Sulphite Company, Mt. Tom, Massachusetts
  - Notebook, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Conference, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Notes for book on Scientific Management, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Press Releases, 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Schwarzenbach Huber Co. - Miscellaneous forms (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Includes payroll records, time records, etc.
  - Schwarzenbach Huber Co. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Rate Forms
  - Schwarzenbach Huber Co. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Weaving Rate Forms
  - Schwarzenbach Huber Co. (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
    Miscellaneous Charts
  - Schwarzenbach Huber Co. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Miscellaneous Forms. Includes expense schedules, earning charts, etc.
  - Schwarzenbach Huber Co. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Miscellaneous
  - Schwarzenbach Huber Co. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Weaving Data
  - "Survey of Wool Spinning Mill...", 1936 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Survey of Wool Spinning Mill...", 1936 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Diagrams
  - Tabor Manufacturing Co. "Instructions for Foundries", 1914 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Tabor Manufacturing Company, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 19-21)
  - Time Study Sheets A-1 and B-2, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Originals
  - Unemployment Conference, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 23-25)
  - Unemployment Conference - Miscellaneous Papers (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Ludlow Manufacturing, Correspondence, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Includes information of time studies
  - Ludlow Manufacturing. Correspondence, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
  - Ludlow Manufacturing. "Daily Doffing Records for Spinning Rooms", 1915 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Ludlow Manufacturing Diagrams, Charts (Box 3, Folder 6-11)
  - Ludlow Manufacturing - Miscellaneous Papers, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 12-14)
  - Ludlow Manufacturing - Miscellaneous Papers, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 15-18)
  - Ludlow Manufacturing - Miscellaneous Papers, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
  - Ludlow Manufacturing - "Time Studies in Winding Dept.", 1916 (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
    February 10, l916
  - Ludlow Manufacturing - Miscellaneous Papers, 1914-1917 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ludlow Manufacturing - Miscellaneous Papers, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Ludlow Manufacturing - Miscellaneous Papers (Box 4, Folder 10)
    no date
- Series II. CORRESPONDENCE, 1892-1949
  - Correspondence, 1892-1893 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1897-1899 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    includes correspondence with Frank Gilbreth
  - Correspondence, 1901-1904 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1901-1904 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    illegible
  - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1907-1914 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1915-1917 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Thompson's copy of a letter to Mrs. F.W. Taylor, regarding a book on the life of F.W. Taylor
  - Correspondence, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1931 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 17-18)
    includes correspondence with E.C. Harwood, Director, American Institute for Economic Research
  - Correspondence, 1936-1938 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1949-1952 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    includes correspondence with F.W. Taylor, Frank Gilbreth
  - Correspondence, 1903-1904 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Series III. PUBLICATIONS, 1925-1946
  - "Adjusting Production to Tomorrow's Market", 1932 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - From Am. Society of Mechanical Engineers, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Application of Costs" (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
  - "Application of Selling and Distribution Costs", 1930 (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
  - "Application of Time Standards in Retail Stores", 1928 (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
  - (W.W. Freeland) "Better Management Pays in Textiles", 1925 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Biographical article with list of selected publications (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "Compensating for Profit Control", 1933 (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
  - "Construction Revival is Essential to Prosperity", 1932 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Contribution to Symposium on F.W. Taylor, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 15-17)
  - Cost Accounting (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Current buying..., 1927 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - (With H.T. Rollins) "The Development of a Modern Hosiery Plant", 1924 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - "Discussion on Distribution Costs", 1933 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - "What Must the Manufacturer Do!" (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - "Engineered Marketing", 1945 (Box 8, Folder 23-24)
  - "Lack of Skill Seen in Marketing Goods", 1932 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous Articles (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Notes for "Engineered Marketing" (Box 8, Folder 27-29)
  - "Increased Production for Defense Needs", 1940 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - "The Influence of Scientific Management" (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - "Labor and Changing Technology", 1940 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - "A New Association for Treatment of Economic Problems", 1932 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - "Optimum Productivity in the Workshop", 1939 (Box 8, Folder 34-35)
  - "Post-War Cost Reductions", 1944 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - "The Quality of Product in Piece-Work" (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - "Relation of Unit Production to Our Business Depression...", 1931 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - "Savings Through Management in Rubber Industry", 1925 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - (Radio Speech) on Salvation Army, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - "Smoothing the Wrinkles from Management", 1927 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - "Stepping Toward Prosperity", 1931 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - "Synchronized Arms Production", 1941 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - "The Taylor Piece-Rate System, Being a Step Toward Partial Solution of the Labor Problem" (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Technological Development (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - "Today's Management and Its Problems", 1936 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - "Unemployment: A Basis for Solution" (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - "What's Holding Back Prosperity?", 1931 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - "Winter Construction", 1926 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Sanford E. Thompson & Edward Smulski. Reinforced Concrete Bridges (Box 9, Folder 1-19)
    Includes manuscript, diagrams, drafts, etc.
  - Sanford E. Thompson & Edward Smulski. Reinforced Concrete Bridges. (Box 10, Folder 1-23)
    Includes index, footnotes, notes, etc.
  - Sanford E. Thompson & Edward Smulski. Reinforced Concrete Bridges (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
    typed manuscript
  - Unpublished Manuscript. Marketing Book, 1946-1947 (Box 11, Folder 4-19)
    Includes notes for the book, chapters, etc.
- Series IV. THOMPSON & LICHTNER COMPANY FILES, 1906-1947
  - "Consulting Practice in Management of Thompson & Lichtner Co." (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Hoover Approach to Current Economic Problems", 1930 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - "A Study of Means to Increase Purchasing Power", 1932 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - "Survey of Opinions of Retailers and Manufacturers", 1946 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - "The Thompson & Lichtner Operating Audit...", 1937 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - "Vertical Integration by Advertising", 1946 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - "Bricklaying", 1902-1908 (Box 12, Folder 7-12)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1947 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Description of Services offered by the Company (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 15)
    Includes information on job evaluation, problems of management, etc.
  - Newsletter: "The Merry Tinker", 1928 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - "History of Scientific Management in America", 1938 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - "Planning for Post-War Costs...", 1944 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - "Problems of Management" (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - "Wage Incentives", 1946 (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Series V. FREDERICK W. TAYLOR FILES 1892-1915
  - Sub-Series 1. R.W. Taylor/Sanford Thompson Correspondence, 1892-1915
    - Correspondence, 1891-1893 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Includes letter of advice from Taylor to Thompson
    - Correspondence, 1894 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1895 (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
    - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 13, Folder 5-8)
    - Correspondence, 1897 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1901-1903 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 13, Folder 11-12)
    - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1906 (Box 13, Folder 14-17)
    - Correspondence, 1907 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1908 (Box 13, Folder 19-22)
    - Correspondence, 1908 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1914 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Taylor/Thompson (?) (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Sub-Series 2. Taylor/Thompson Experiment Documents 1905-1915
    - Concrete Experiments Data, 1907 (Box 14, Folder 1-16)
      Contains data pertaining to these experiments. Included are letters, notes, etc. Some are illegible
    - Soil and grass experiments, 1910 (Box 15, Folder 1-5)
      Correspondence - S. Thompson with H. Van DuZee
    - Soil and grass experiments, 1912-1915 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Soil and grass experiments (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Charts, diagrams, no date
    - Soil and grass experiments, 1909 (Box 15, Folder 8-13)
      Computation sheets, instructions
    - Soil and grass experiments, 1910 (Box 15, Folder 14-19)
      Computation sheets
    - Soil and grass experiments, 1911 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Soil and grass experiments, 1912 (Box 15, Folder 21-22)
    - Soil and grass experiments. Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 23)
      Includes general notes, instructions of F. W. Taylor, etc.
  - Sub-Series 3. A. Miscellaneous Taylor Files 1892-1963
    - "Principles of Scientific Management", "Success"., 1906-1912 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Articles, 1911-1914 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1891-1892 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Manufacturing Instruments Company letters
    - Correspondence, 1901-1914 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Includes correspondence with Frank Gilbreth.
    - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Richard Feiss, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      March 11, l915. Letter refers to Taylor's visit to Feiss factory. Written a few days prior to Taylor's death.
    - Letter establishing F.W. Taylor Co-operators, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      May 11, l915. Carl Barth, Morris Cooke, James Dodge, H.K. Hathaway
    - Miscellaneous Information on Taylor (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - F. W. Taylor. Patents (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Professional Papers, 1892 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Professional Papers. Consulting Data for Philadelphia Civil Service Commission, 1912-1913 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Professional Papers. Consulting Data for Philadelphia Civil Service, 1913-1914 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Professional Papers. "Pig Iron Reports" (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Professional Papers. Photographs, Diagrams (Box 16, Folder 14)